-==破爛熊樂園傾情奉獻==-
本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業用途
-=破爛熊字幕組=-
翻譯：choc 青色石頭
校對&時間軸：小魎
顯然 我錯誤估算了一些事情
Obviously, I miscalculated a few things.
艾迪 我知道你就在裡面
Eddie! I know you're in there!
如果某天 生活遠遠脫離了正常的夢想...
Why is it that the moment your life exceeds your wildest dreams...
你輸入的密碼...
The access code you have entered...
而問題又如芒在刺
The knife appears at your back?
你輸入的密碼有誤...
The access code you have entered is invalid...
好吧 聽我說...
Well, I'll tell you one thing...
我絕不會讓他們碰我一指頭
I will never let them touch me.
我的鄰居 一定已經開門抱怨了
My neighbor, who must have opened his door to complain.
下一個就是你了 艾迪 我們進來了
You're gonna be next, Eddie! We're coming in!
對一個擁有四位數智商的人 我一定錯過了什麼
For a guy with a four digit IQ, I must have missed something.
卻並不多
And I hadn't missed much.
距離影響整個世界只有一步之遙
I'd come this close to having an impact on the world.
而現在 唯一會受到我行為影響的只有...
And now, the only thing I'd have an impact on...
...人行道
...was the sidewalk.
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
永無止境
看見那個傢伙了嗎
You see that guy?
就是我 不久之前的我
That was me, not so long ago.
除了癮君子和酒鬼 還有誰能這幅德行
What kind of guy without a drug or alcohol problem looks this way?
毫無疑問只有作家 說來也怪
Only a writer. Strangely enough,
居然沒人願意相信我還有書約在身
nobody believed that I actually had a book contract.
嗯 雖然是以科幻小說的形式
Well, it's masquerading as a sci-fi novel,
但我的本意是想表現
but it's really, uh, my own personal manifesto
身處21世紀個人的困境
about the plight of the individual in the 21st century.
我創造出了一個烏托邦的社會
I sort of created a utopian society
而在那個社會裡...我們...嗯...
where we all sort of... Uh... Uh...
非常的...真的...
It's really... it's really...
呃...
Uh...
今天一定要寫出點什麼
Today was the day I was gonna kick its ass.
來吧 來吧 加油...
Here we go. Here we go. Here we go...
一定會很棒的
It was gonna be great.
只要待在房間裡 肯花上時間
Just gotta put in the time. Stay in the room.
這就是關鍵
That's the key concept.
不能離開房間
Don't leave the room.
就這樣過去了幾周
A few weeks passed this way.
也許是之後的幾個月
Maybe a few months.
至少我還有琳迪
At least I still had Lindy.
就這樣嗎
Just like that?
行了 艾迪 這也算是意料之中的事了
Come on, Eddie, This is hardly a surprise,
完全意料之外
I'm surprised,
別這樣 好吧 讓我...
Let's just not do this, OK? Let me...
我週五就要交給瑪勒90頁的稿子
I'm gonna hand in 90 pages to Marla on Friday,
你不如等等看她的評價再...
If you just wait to see what she says...
艾迪
Eddie,
什麼      我明白的
What?        I know how it's going,
我是你的...
I'm your...
我曾經是你的女朋友
I was your girlfriend,
但這個詞卻不能充分說明你對於我的意義
That word doesn't even begin to describe what you are to me,
夥伴? 洩慾對像?
Partner? Squeeze?
愛侶 戀人
Paramour, Inamorata,
清掃女工 還有自動提款機
Cleaning lady, Bank,
謝謝 馬上給您送過來
Thanks, Be right back,
只是...
Be that a...
但我的東西也都是你的啊
What's mine is yours, too,
你很清楚 我願意與你共度餘生
and you know I want to share the rest of my life with you,
我想過也許我們應該...      別求婚 千萬別
I was thinking that we should...        Don't propose,
為什麼
Why not?
因為上一段婚姻就讓你精疲力竭
Because it worked out so well for you last time,
這倒是真的 我結過婚 剛畢業的時候 和梅利莎
It's true, I did marry once. Right out of college, to Melissa.
我願意
I do,
不過非常短暫
Briefly.
我做不到
This isn't working,
好吧 就算你說的都是真的 但我還是愛你啊
Well, even though everything you say is true, I still love you,
我得回去工作了
I gotta get back to work,
你還沒告訴我為什麼啊
You didn't even tell me what happened,
我做到了      真的嗎
I got it,        You did?
嗯哼 我是個編輯了
Mm-hm, I'm an editor,
有自己的助理 你能相信嗎
I'll have my own assistant, Can you believe that?
我當然相信啊 這是你應得的啊
Yeah, of course I believe it, You deserve it,
謝謝
Thanks,
好了      好吧
OK,        OK,
她是對的 那為什麼還要堅持下去呢
She was right. Why stick it out?
顯而易見 我已經錯失良機
I had clearly missed the on-ramp.
我們都清楚真正動人心弦的是什麼
We both knew what was beckoning.
在新澤西我孩提時代臥室的下鋪
The lower bunk in my childhood bedroom in Jersey.
父親滿心歡喜地迎接我來到
My father happy to welcome me into the challenging field
牙科器械這一充滿挑戰的領域
of dental supply inventory.
艾迪·莫萊
Eddie Morra,
在所有該被棄之敝履
Of all the useless relationships better forgotten
束之高閣的無用人際關係中
and put away in mothballs,
有什麼能比得上前小舅子更無用
is there any more useless than... the ex-brother-in-law?
要死了 老兄
Holy shit, man,
是有多久了 9年有沒有
What has it been? Like nine years?
老天爺      嘿
God!        Hey,
你還好嗎 怎麼一副淪落街頭的樣子
You all right? You look like you're living on the streets,
過得如何
What's going on?
不算..我..嗯..我..你呢
Not much, I... Well... What am I... What's up?
嗯 寫東西吧 寫了不少
Uh, I'm writing, Writing a lot,
哦 你還沒放棄寫東西嗎
Oh, you're still trying to write?
事實上 我還有書約在身
Matter of fact, I have a book contract,
真的嗎      是的
Really?        Yeah,
那很好啊      你呢
That's great,        How about you?
還在販藥嗎 弗恩
Are you still dealing, Vern?
我看起來還像幹這行的嗎      這倒是不像
Do I look like I'm still dealing?        No, you don't, No,
走吧 去喝一杯 給我說說你的書
Come on, let's go get a drink, I want to hear about this book,
不是吧 現在可是下午2點啊
I don't know, It's 2:00 in the afternoon,
這個時間你有什麼問題嗎
When has that ever stopped you?
怎麼說      那...
So,        So...
梅利莎過得好嗎
How's Melissa doing?
給      謝謝
Here you go,        Thanks,
不知道 沒見過她 她搬家了 去了北部
Wouldn't know, I don't see her, She moved upstate,
好像在做什麼網絡房屋銷售的玩意
She got some kind of Internet home sales kind of job,
帶著一大堆孩子
Couple kids,
孩子 那她老公呢
Couple kids, Who's the husband?
離了 如果你問的是這個
He walked out on her, if you really want to know,
不過這和你沒什麼關係吧
But what do you care, man?
算起來你們兩個也就結了5分鐘的婚
You were married, like, five minutes,
聽著 我不想談她 不如說說你吧
Look, I don't wanna talk about her, I wanna talk about you, OK?
說說你的書 進展如何
Tell me about this book, How's it going?
嗯 書的話 呃...
Well, it's, uh...
我...我...
I'm... I'm...
我只是在逃避 用書來做借口逃避
I'm behind, I'm behind on my book,
而這個借口差不多毀了我日日夜夜的生活
And, uh, it's pretty well polluting my days and nights,
如果那是你想知道的
if you really want to know,
嗯 你已經寫了多少呢      一片空白
Well, how much have you written of it?        Not one word,
靈感的問題 是嗎      算是吧
Creative problems, huh?        Yeah, Mm-hm,
說不定我能幫上忙
Well, I suppose I can help you with that,
不過僅此一次
Just this once,
哦 不用 真的不用了
Oh, no, no, no, no, no,
你根本不知道這是什麼      你還在販藥嗎
You don't even know what it is,        You're still dealing,
老兄 我不幹那玩意兒很多年了
Brother, I am light years from that now,
現在我可是某家製藥企業的顧問
I've been doing, uh, some consulting for a pharmaceutical company,
什麼企業 沿海那些做山寨偉哥的實驗室嗎
What, like some offshore lab making fake Viagra?
得了 弗恩
Come on, Vern,
不是 這可是明年就會批量生產的高檔貨
No, This is an exclusive product that's coming on stream next year,
已經通過了臨床試驗和食藥局的認可
They've had clinical trials and it's FDA approved,
好吧 就算純粹好奇心作祟吧 這...
All right, just out of curiosity and that's all...
拿出來看看吧
Let's see it,
這到底是什麼
What's in it?
專家已經證實大腦裡的受體
They've identified these receptors in the brain
都被觸發了特殊的回路
that activate specific circuits,
知道他們都怎麼說嗎 我們使用的只有大腦的20%
And you how they say that we can only access 20 percent of our brain?
然而 這個東西...卻能讓你完全利用自己的大腦
Well, what this does... it lets you access all of it,
弗恩 看看我 算得上事業有成嗎
Vern, look at me, Do I look good to you?
不過是個一無是處的倒霉蛋
I'm broke and I'm depressed off my ass,
我不覺得這麼一小片反光的新型藥丸
I don't think that my life's gonna take some sudden upswing
能帶來翻天覆地的變化 讓我名利兩全
into fame and fortune by taking some shiny, brand-new designer drug,
甘特
Gant,
什麼時候
When?
告訴他不行 不 你告訴他
Tell him we can't do that, No, you tell him,
不行 就是現在
No, now,
抱歉我得先走了 艾迪
Well, I'm afraid I'm gonna have to leave you here, Eddie,
但我真的...真的還想再多說一句
But I really... I really do want to do this again,
所以 記得給我電話 這份算是送你的了
So, call me, And, uh, that's on the house,
我不需要
I don't want it,
別不知足 知道這要多少錢嗎
Don't be ungrateful, You know how much that costs?
800塊 就這麼一小粒
Eight hundred bucks, A pop,
別客氣
You're welcome,
在回家的路上 我滿腦子想得都是梅利莎
All the way home, I thought about Melissa.
她的生活怎麼也會變得一團糟 她這麼聰明
How could she be a failure, too? She'd been so smart.
比周圍所有人都聰明
Smarter than anyone around her.
顯然 當下的艾迪 和今天下午3點微醉的艾迪
Clearly, there was a direct link between this Eddie,
甚至和過往那個吐在老闆桌上的
slightly drunk at 3:00 in the afternoon, and an earlier Eddie...
偷走將死姑媽止疼藥的艾迪總有著直接聯繫
...vomiting on his boss's desk or stealing his dying aunt's Percocet.
所以無怪乎琳迪會棄我而去了
So who could blame Lindy for dumping me?
說到底 還能有多糟糕呢
In the end, how much worse could it get?
我什麼人都不想見
I didn't want to see anybody.
尤其是房東那位惡毒的小妻子
Especially not my landlord's nasty young wife.
瓦萊利 才週二呢      聽著 我受夠了 明白嗎
Valerie, Tuesday,        Look, Enough, OK?
是斯蒂文在處理房租 他也許吃你那套
Steve handles the rent, so you can feed your crap to him,
我突然有了擺脫她更好的理由
I suddenly had extra reason to get away from her.
我剛剛稀里糊塗地吞下了某種藥物
I had thoughtlessly ingested a substance.
好像房租總不夠便宜似的
Like the rent's not low enough!
關於這個藥物的效果 我只從弗農那裡
I had gotten remarkably little information from Vernon
獲得了少得可憐的信息
about what this drug would do.
就算你現在騎車去送報也還來得及 我說真的
You could even be a bike messenger and come up with that, Really,
如果這是迷幻藥又會怎樣      真是毫無指望
What if it was a hallucinogen?        It's pathetic,
哦 上帝啊 看她沒完沒了的碎碎念...
Oh, my God. Listening to her rag...
如果我是你的話 早就直接跳窗了
If I were tripping, I'd jump out a fucking window.
嘿 你有沒有在聽我說
Hello? Are you listening to me?
你還不懂 是不是 你就等著滾去睡大街吧
Do you get it? You are gonna be out on the streets!
然後 我突然感覺到了
And then, I felt it.
之前我是盲目的 現在才終於看清了一切
I was blind, but now I see.
...趕緊給我走 都不敢看我的眼睛 知道為啥麼
...running away! You can't even look at me, you know why?
因為你根本不算是個男人 根本就不是個男人
Because you're not even a man, You're not even a man!
不付房租 沒有工作
You don't have rent! You don't have a job!
你怎麼了      什麼
What's wrong?        What?
你不喜歡我 我不怪你 在你眼裡 我是個一無是處
You don't like me and I don't blame you, You see a self-defeating,
浪費生命 靠你丈夫施捨過日子的混球
energy-sucking piece of shit who's sponging off your husband,
你樂見我飲彈自盡
You're wishing I'd blow my brains out,
但我的存在並不該讓你覺得不安 到底為什麼呢
but my existence shouldn't make you this upset, What is it?
和你有什麼關係      是法學院的課程不順利嗎
That's none of your business,        Something wrong at law school?
你怎麼知道我在念法律
How do you know I'm in law school?
沒有幾個正常人會隨身帶著
People who aren't, usually don't carry around dry,
這種讀來無趣 某位已故高院法官的迂腐之作
academically-constipated books about a dead Supreme Court justice,
你個變態 你...你跟蹤我是不是
You're a creep, aren't you? You've been... You've been following me,
不是 我只是看到書而已      你才看到一個角
No, I just noticed the book,        You just saw the corner of it,
怎麼能確定
How did you know that?
我之前看過 12年前 還在大學的時候
I'd seen it before. Twelve years ago in college.
坐在一個助教的沙發上
Sitting on the couch of a TA I was trying to make,
等著她沐浴歸來
waiting for her to come back out of the bathroom,
希冀她能有一個保險套
hoping she'd have a condom.
突然之間這個信息就從潛意識中蹦了出來
Somehow my unconscious had served that up.
一段從未被我刻意記憶的片段
A memory I had never even recorded.
或者說 長久以來 我需要的只是一把鑰匙
Or was it there the whole time and all I needed was the access?
如果你要寫論文 這本書絕不是上佳選擇
If you're writing a paper, that's not the book I'd use,
哈 誰問你意見了
Well, who asked you?
黑斯廷斯有自己的口述歷史
Hastings has his oral history,
要是我 就會從那裡著手
I'd start there,
有趣的是 基本而言 他就是個白癡
Interesting point, Grammatically, this guy was an idiot,
他曾經解雇的一位員工
which sort of gives credence to the theory
能寫出他大部分的觀點
that one of the clerks he had fired
這種傢伙的理論 有誰願意相信
actually wrote most of this guy's major opinions,
你可以谷歌一下那位僱員的子孫
You could Google the clerk's sons,
相信他們非常樂意和你交談
they'd love to talk to you,
為他們父親脫罪
Exonerate their dad,
也許能給到你一些無人知曉的東西...
That'd give you something that no one else has...
古怪博物館展覽的信息 半知半解的文字
Information from the odd museum show, a half-read article,
公共廣播公司的某些文檔...突然涌到我的額葉
some PBS documentary... it was all bubbling up in my frontal lobes,
自我混合成最絢麗最有用的信息雞尾酒
mixing itself together into a sparkling cocktail of useful information.
她毫無機會      那你有什麼建議呢
She didn't have a chance.        So, what are your suggestions?
我們確實為她的論文做了不少工作
We'd really worked on her paper, too.
但45分鐘後 就演變成了另一種活動
In 45 minutes, it was a polished gem.
她顯然也得到了滿足
She was pleased.
家 但這裡真的是我的家嗎
Home. But it couldn't be my home, could it?
有誰能忍受住在這樣的地方
Who would live like this?
真想一把火燒了這裡
My first thought was Torch it.
但理智佔了上風
But saner heads prevailed.
這算是什麼毒品 完全沒有上癮後的混亂
What was this drug? I couldn't stay messy on it,
6個小時沒抽一支煙 沒有進食...
I hadn't had a cigarette in six hours, hadn't eaten,
那麼是整潔和節制嗎
so... abstemious and tidy?
這算什麼呢 讓人記憶力更強的毒品嗎
What was this? A drug for people who wanted to be more anal retentive?
我不興奮也不乖張 只是出人意料的清醒
I wasn't high, I wasn't wired. Just clear.
很清楚自己想做什麼 該如何去做
I knew what I needed to do and how to do it.
第二天清晨 我小小探索了一下自己的大腦
The next morning, I sent a little probe down into my brain.
毫無任何的澎湃思緒和靈感閃現
No surge of brilliance came up to greet me.
短暫的光彩過後...我還是我
In short... I was back.
但是 有些東西卻留了下來
But, something remained.
開玩笑吧你
You're kidding,
沒有      居然有白紙黑字裝訂成冊
No,        Words have appeared on paper,
是的      還能是出自你手
Yes,        Written by you,
只求你能看上三張
All you have to do is read three pages,
就花一個小時看上三張 然後...
Just read three pages in the next hour and...
...如果你沒興趣讀下去 我就把預付款還你
...if you don't want to keep reading, I'll give you back the advance,
好嗎
OK,
可以 艾迪      好的
OK, Eddie,        OK,
艾迪 回來了給我電話
Eddie, give me a call when you get in.
艾迪 我又看了40頁 給我電話
Eddie, I'm 40 pages further in. Call me.
雖然有些小做作 不過我還在看
It's a little grandiose, but I'm still reading.
說吧 你怎麼做到的
OK, how did you do this?
我真的很喜歡...一回來就給我電話 別忘了
I'd really like... Just call me the minute you get in. Call. OK?
誰啊      嘿 弗農 是我 艾迪
Who is it?        Hey, Vernon, it's Eddie,
哪個艾迪      嗯 我是莫萊
Eddie who?        Uh, Morra,
現在不是時候 艾迪
It's not a good time, Eddie,
呃 嘿 弗恩 我真的需要和你談談
Uh, hey, Vern, I really just need to talk to you,
嘿...哦...
Hey... Oh...
弗恩 出什麼事了      別擔心 我沒事
Vern, what happened?        Don't worry about it, I'm fine,
好吧 艾迪 你還是有興趣了
So, Eddie, You are interested after all,
這玩意兒太神奇了
That stuff's amazing,
如果你夠聰明 就更有效果了
Works better if you're already smart,
弗恩 誰把你打成這樣的
Vern, who did this to you?
相信我 你不會想知道的
Trust me, you don't want to know,
呃...
Uh...
那 這個叫什麼來著      在市面上還沒有名字
So, uh, what's it called?        Doesn't have a street name yet,
但是那些藥劑師都叫它NZT 48
But the boys in the kitchen are calling it NZT 48,
"藥劑師" 我不知道...
"The boys in the kitchen"? I don't...
聽起來不怎麼像是被食藥局認可的藥品啊 弗恩
That doesn't sound very FDA-approved, Vern,
食藥局認可 說什麼笑話呢
FDA-approved, that's a laugh,
你不會真相信了吧
You didn't really believe that shit, did ya?
好吧 現在是什麼狀況
OK, so what do we have here?
某種未知的 未經測試 有潛在危險的藥片
Some unknown, untested, possibly dangerous drug
從某身份未明的實驗室流落出來
scammed out of some unidentified lab somewhere
經由一個我多年未見 極不可信的傢伙交到我手中
given to me by a highly unreliable guy I hadn't seen in years.
你還想要嗎      是的 當然
So you want some more?        Yes, Definitely,
好吧 這個稍後再談 但現在我需要有人幫個忙
All right, we'll talk about it, but I, uh, need a favor first,
顯然 我現在這個樣子是沒法出門的
Obviously, I'm in no condition to go out right now, so,
我在想你能不能為我
I was wondering if you could pop down
去取一下送洗的西裝
to the dry cleaners, grab my suit for me,
順便再幫我弄點..早飯什麼的
And maybe grab a little... A little breakfast for us,
他很清楚已經牢牢控制住了我
He knew he had me.
好吧
Sure,
從此刻開始 我很樂意成為他的專屬小弟
From now on, I'd happily be his errand boy.
洗窗 擦馬桶...
Wash his windows, scrub his toilet...
...任何事情我都願意 只要能讓那個
...anything I could do to get my hands on that little clear pill
升級版的艾迪重新回來
that would bring back... Enhanced Eddie.
弗恩
Vern?
弗恩...
哦 弗恩
Oh, Vern,
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey!
嘿
Hey!
911 請問有什麼緊急情況      嘿 我想報警...
911, what's your emergency?        Hi, I need to report a...
...是一起謀殺
...a murder,
7B 是的
7B, yes,
好的 我不會的
OK, I won't,
像是等了一世紀 而我站得越久 看得越是明白
Took them forever. And the longer I stood there, the clearer I saw.
弗恩知道兇手是誰
Vern had known whoever had done this.
也明白他們在找的是什麼
And one guess what they'd been looking for.
但他們找到了嗎
But had they found it?
要命 如果你是自己開伙 那我這條命也交代了
Shit, if you ever cooked, I'd be dead, too,
我們是警察 請開門
Police Department! Open the door, please!
我們是警察 開門
Police Department! Open the door!
請立刻開門
Open the door, please!
我們是警察 開門
Police! Open the door!
我們進去 開門
Let's go! Open the door!
把手舉起來      嘿
Let me see your hands,        Hey,
把手舉起來      不是我 不 是我報的警
Let me see your hands!        No, no, I'm the one who called!
是我叫你們來的
I called you guys!
這麼說 你們的關係不錯咯 經常一起出入嗎
So, you guys tight? Hang out a lot?
也不算是 他是我前妻的兄弟
No, my ex-wife's brother,
我也只是才和他在路上遇到
I just actually ran into him on the street
然後他讓我上去坐坐...
and he asked me to come up to...
再買點毒品什麼的嗎
Buy some drugs?
不 不是的 什麼意思      這傢伙做什麼的
No, no, What?        What did this guy do?
他...嗯 我不知道 他之前 嗯...
He... Uh, I don't know, He was, um...
聽說他之前是個古董販賣商
I heard that he was an antiques dealer?
販賣商嗎      是的 嗯 古董方面的 嗯...
A dealer?        Yeah, uh, antiques, Um...
好像是 維也納風格的...
Like, uh, Viennese kinda, um...
...椅子什麼的
...chairs and stuff,
就像是 你知道的 那種圈腿椅之類的
Like, you know, like curlicue leg things,
你好
Yeah?
沒錯 是有一位艾德華·莫萊
That is correct, An Edward Morra,
他就在這裡
He's here,
受害者的妹妹
Victim's sister,
我已經有10年沒有聽到她的聲音了
I hadn't heard her voice in ten years.
艾迪      梅利莎
Eddie?        Melissa?
你當時在場嗎      是的...
You were there?        Um...
我之前正好在街上遇到他 所以 是的...
Just before, I had run into him on the street and, uh... yeah,
哦 上帝
Oh, God.
我都不覺得奇怪 他是捲入了件麻煩裡
I wish I was more surprised. He was involved in some stuff.
我不應該多說的
I'd better not say any more.
是的 沒錯 這也許是個好主意
No, no, that's probably a good idea,
那麼 嗯...也許我們應該見個面什麼的
So, uh... We should probably, uh, meet or something, right?
不用了 我還要處理喪禮還有各種亂七八糟的事
No, I gotta do the funeral and God knows what else.
我只是...
I just...
我們不能見面 好嗎
We can't meet, OK?
好吧 嗯 我只是...
Right, Well, I'll just...
那葬禮上見吧
I guess I'll just see you at the funeral then,
不了 我不想 別這樣 再聯繫吧 好嗎
No. I don't want that. Please don't. I'll call you at some point, OK?
等事情都結束了      好的 那就這樣吧
When this is over.        OK, all right,
好的
OK.
要知道 現在有些事情還不明朗
You know, something doesn't gel here,
留下你的電話 稍後也許會再聯繫你
Write down your number, I may need to contact you later,
值得冒這個風險嗎
Worth the risk?
如果是你 會如何呢
What would you do?
弗恩留下的現金 加上一些前所未有潮涌的衝動
Vern's cash, combined with an unprecedented surge of motivation,
促使我在4天裡面完成了一整本小說
enabled me to finish the book in four days.
一天一片
A tablet a day
每天的時間都是如此有限而珍貴
and what I could do with my day was limitless.
我在3天裡學會了彈奏鋼琴
I learned to play the piano in three days.
數學變得有用
Math became useful.
而充滿奇趣
And fun.
全跟
I'm all in,
只是半知半解 已足以讓我熟練運用一門新語言
Even half-listening to any language, I became fluent.
那你覺得莎士比亞抖的小包袱其實很普通咯
So that Shakespeare's catchiness belies mediocrity?
毫無爭辯之意
There's no arguing with you,
這種感覺太棒了
This was great.
聽我說 媽媽 關於海倫姑媽的腫瘤 我做了些研究
So, Mom, I've been doing a little research on Aunt Helen's tumor,
非常明確的一點就是
And it's totally clear that
任何罹患此類家族性腺瘤性息肉的人
anybody with familial adenomatous polyposis
應當接受含鉑類雙重
should be supplementing platinum-based doublet regiments
二十碳五烯酸補充治療
with eicosapentaeonic acid,
突然之間我變得無所不知 無所不曉
I suddenly knew everything. About everything.
當然 這只是一個短期的刺激
Well, sure, you get a short-term spike,
但過快的增長
but wouldn't that rapid expansion
是否會導致兩年內股票的徹底貶值呢
devalue that stock completely in two years?
不會 因為安全機制的存在
No, because there are safeguards,
限制了侵略性過度膨脹?
Against aggressive over-expansion?
沒有用的 在人性中不存在所謂的安全機制
There aren't, Because there are no safeguards in human nature,
過猶不及通常帶來失敗
We're wired to overreach,
回顧整個歷史 看看那些曾顛覆世界的國家
Look at history, all the countries that ever ruled the world,
葡萄牙曾擁有大量傲視當世的海軍
Portugal with this big massive navy,
現在呢 只剩下了醃鱈魚和廉價保險套
All they got now are salt cod and cheap condoms,
更別說曾經的日不落帝國了
And the Brits?
只能蝸居在潮濕陰冷的島國
Now they're just sitting on a dank little island
為明天的西裝憂心不已
fussing over their suits,
為什麼就沒人願意停下思考一下
No one's stopping and thinking,
"嘿 我們已經做得很好了
"Hey, we're doing pretty well,
佔領了法國 波蘭還有瑞士銀行裡巨大的存款
We got France, we got Poland, we got a big Swiss bank account,
為什麼還要大冷天的跑去侵略什麼俄羅斯
You know what? Let's not invade Russia in the winter,
踏實回家 舉杯慶祝 依靠這些利息頤養天年吧"
Let's go home, let's pop a beer, and let's live off the interest,"
說的沒錯
Yeah,
這些所思所感如潮水般從我腦中涌出
My brain was just pouring this stuff out.
所有我曾經讀過 聽過 看過的東西
Everything I had ever read, heard, seen
都變成了條理分明 隨時可用的觀點
was now organized and available.
就是這裡 你到了
Here it is. Here you go.
艾迪 嘿 聽我說 我想你應該在做一些投資
Eddie, Hey, Listen, I'm sure you have a portfolio,
當然如果沒有的話 我非常樂意和你一起工作
but if you don't, I'd be very interested in working with you,
好的 凱文
OK, Kevin,
我結交了新朋友 應邀前往海灘
I made some new friends who invited me to the beach.
當然不是近在眼前的海灘
The beach was not nearby.
曾經的戰戰兢兢和羞澀靦腆 都離我而去
All my fear, all my shyness, gone.
他們做了四次基本審查...
They've done four basic trials...
但只是懶散度日並不足夠
But mere lounging wasn't enough.
唯一麻煩是 如果無法繼續前進
Only problem? If I wasn't moving forward,
我一定會承受不了而崩潰
I felt like I was going to explode.
快過來 這裡太美了 是不是
Come up here because it's beautiful, right?
有人想試試看嗎      你瘋了吧
Anybody ever jump?        Are you crazy?
他真的會跳的      別扯了
He's gonna do it,        He's not gonna do it,
哦 上帝
Oh, my God!
哦
Oh!
啊
Ah!
就在此刻我有了主意
And then I began to form an idea.
我突然明白了該做的到底是什麼
Suddenly, I knew exactly what I needed to do.
無關創造 更無關書本
It wasn't writing. It wasn't books.
遠甚於這些
It was much bigger than that.
但我需要足夠的錢來完成這一切
But it would take money to get there.
在下游市場 沒有人能賺到足夠的資本
In a down market, no one was making much.
同樣這些人也沒有NZT
But no one had NZT.
以最樂觀的預計
In an optimistic scenario,
這種自然的收益只能反映
gains of that nature merely would reflect
經濟的增長 而並不會造成任何障礙的產生...
growth in the economy and would not pose an obstacle...
用弗恩剩下的最後800塊 在一天之內賺了2000
Armed with Vern's last $800, I made 2,000 in a day.
第二天 變成了7500
Next day, 7,500.
還是太慢 我需要更多的資金
It was too slow. I'd need more capital.
但銀行不會貸款給我這樣的人
But banks weren't lending to guys like me.
嘿 利夫
Hey, Liev,
你要找的人就坐在角落裡
That's your man in the corner back there,
好的
Yeah,
利夫應該已經和你說了 我想找筆短期借貸
So, uh, Liev told you that I'm looking for a short-term loan?
是的 我讓利夫拉倒吧
Yeah, and I told Liev forget it,
為什麼
Why?
因為我不認識你 更他媽的開始不喜歡你了
Because I don't see you before and I don't fucking like you already,
所以我為什麼要借你十萬呢
Why do I give you $100,000?
因為...
Because...
...我有能力在四天之內讓這些錢漲五倍
...I quintupled my money four days in a row,
這麼說 你有內幕消息嗎
So you got a fix on the game,
不 不算是
No, not a fix,
我只是運用一些計算法則得出了某些定式
I was able to calculate certain patterns using algorithms,
如果你看下第四欄的話 是第一...
If you look at column four, this was the first...
你說的沒錯
You're good,
我是有消息
OK, it's a fix,
要知道 你們這種人總會被逮住的
Yeah, you know, all you people get caught,
到時候你要怎麼辦
What are you gonna do then?
至少我沒有什麼寫有你大名的黑名冊
Well, it's not as if I have a black book with your name in it,
如果你關心的是這個問題
if that's what you're talking about,
此外 我有很強的預感
And besides, I get the strong feeling
我絕不願意輕易讓你失望
that you're not somebody I want to disappoint,
別起來 我說了別起來
Don't get up, I said don't get up,
坐好了      嘿 好的
Sit down!        Hey, OK,
拿了這錢 你的小命就是我的了      好的
OK, you take this, you mine,        OK,
聽好了 如果到時候不還錢 後果你很清楚吧
You understand? You don't pay, you know what we do?
我會直接腰斬了你
I cut you at waist,
剝了你的皮 綁到你腦袋頂上去
Peel your skin up over your head and tie knot in it,
窒息這玩意兒 你絕不會想死那麼難看
You don't die from this, You suffocate,
好的      祝你好運了
OK,        Good luck,
我的新朋友 凱文·道爾 教會了我
My new friend, Kevin Doyle, showed me how you could leverage
如何在當日交易公司 讓一塊錢變成兩塊半
two and a half times your cash at the day trading firm.
一周以來 我不斷的增加用量
I'd been upping the dose for over a week.
似乎確實縮短了我的學習曲線
It seemed to cut my learning curve.
為什麼要買這個 他們的CEO剛剛受到控告
Why are you buying that? The CEO was just indicted,
但並不是因為他賄賂的事情
But not for the big fat defense contract he bribed his way into,
還會上漲的 下周就會宣佈
That's still on, Should be announced next week,
我剛剛黑入了系統 重新啟動
I was jacked in. Booted up.
在週末 我的經紀人賬戶
At the end of the week, my brokerage account
已經超過了兩百萬
contained over two million dollars.
消息傳得很快
Word quickly got out.
19條新信息
You have 19 messages.
4個工作機會 銀行提高了我的信用額度
Four job offers, my bank raising my line of credit,
紐約郵報專訪報道
a reporter from the New York Post,
一定給我回電 莫萊先生
Really call me back, Mr. Morra.
沒有人能在這麼短的時間內累計財富
No one makes money that fast.
不管你是否出現 這篇文章登定了
This article's gonna get written with or without you.
最終 凱文·道爾帶來了好消息
And finally, Kevin Doyle trying to sound casual.
艾迪 我和我的老闆談過你的事情
Eddie, I was talking you up to my boss
最不可能的事情居然成真了 老兄
and, well, the impossible happened, bud.
我們給你安排了和卡爾·范隆的碰面
We got you a meeting with Carl Van Loon.
卡爾·范隆要見你嗎
Carl Van Loon wants to meet you?
顯然是有這麼回事      但你不並擅長金融行業
Apparently so,        But you're not in the finance game,
你能幫卡爾·范隆做什麼
What can you do for Carl Van Loon?
你什麼時候學的意大利語
Since when do you speak Italian?
哦 自我提升的幾個月吧
Oh, Self-improvement month,
大概是誰點醒了我吧
I guess somebody gave me a wake up call,
希望不是因為我
I hope you didn't do it for me,
不 我只是希望能向你道歉 琳
No, I just wanted to apologize to you, Lin,
讓你明白 我的自我毀滅
And let you know that apparently my capacity for self-sabotage
並非無下限
wasn't boundless after all,
而我真正想知道的是 為什麼要這樣容忍我
The real question is, why did you ever put up with me?
因為那時候我愛你
I was in love with you,
嗯 書什麼時候出版
So, when does the book come out?
明年吧 你的新助理怎麼樣
Next year, How's your new assistant?
還挺好的      那就好
She's good,        Good,
嗯      好的
Yeah,        Yeah,
那你 嗯 有沒有新...
And, uh, are you gonna get a new...
聽我說...你能來 我真的很高興
You know... I'm really happy you're here with me,
我為你驕傲 而且...
I'm proud of you, And...
...更有些威脅感
...a little intimidated,
我們又重新開始了
We started up again.
她家
Her place.
我家
My place.
任何地方
Basically every place.
"在3天火熱的交易中
"In a sizzling three days of trading,
這位莫萊先生顛覆了整個市場
the unknown Mr. Morra trumped the market,
引用某位對沖基金經理的評論
prompting one top hedge fund manager to comment:
'他就是霍迪尼 我們這個時代的預言家'"
'He's Houdini, He's a prophet of our times,"'
好了 給我 快給我啦
OK, give me that, Give me that!
"他是上帝"      晚點過來嗎
"He's God"?        You coming over later?
不行 我可沒有鑰匙
I can't, I don't have a key,
哦 也是
Oh, that's right,
那我能拿回來嗎      嗯...別想
Can I have it back?        Uh... Nope,
不行嗎      我想說的是 一定是要原來那把嗎
No?        I mean, does it have to be that key?
不能有一把新鑰匙嗎
Can it be a new key?
我們家的新鑰匙
To our place?
這代價可不小啊      你是說我不夠務實
It would be cost effective,        And you say I'm not practical,
我送你去上班吧
Can I walk you to work?
看什麼呢 親愛的
Whatcha doing, hon?
沒事
Nothing,
該睡覺了
You should sleep,
明天不是還要去見范隆嗎
Isn't your Van Loon meeting tomorrow?
艾迪
Eddie?
你還好嗎
Are you OK?
你在這裡幹什麼
What are you doing out here?
你上次是什麼時候吃的飯
When's the last time you ate something?
看這是誰啊 郵報上的文章不錯啊 老兄
There he is, Nice article in the Post, buddy,
好吧 他就在過來的路上
OK, he is on his way,
現在 聽好了 這個人反覆無常
Now, be warned, He's mercurial,
前一秒 可能是你最好的朋友
One minute, your best friend,
而下一秒 就對你避之不及
the next, you're a leper,
他需要的是最為直接的答覆
And he needs direct answers,
任何的試探猶豫都會讓你錯失良機
Anything tentative and you've lost him forever,
我們應該排練一下的
I think we should rehearse a few scenarios,
凱文 我還在吃東西
I'm eating, Kevin,
嘿 你就是來吃東西的嗎
Hey, are you up for this?
你確定嗎 我可是冒了很大風險
You sure? 'Cause I got a little bit on the line here,
來點吐司吧
Have a toast point,
是卡爾·范隆      是卡爾·范隆
It's Carl Van Loon,        That's Carl Van Loon,
財富的象徵
He's worth a fortune,
嘿 約翰      嘿 卡爾 見到你很高興
Hey, John,        Hey, Carl, Good to see you,
你好啊      艾迪
How are ya?        Eddie,
那麼 艾迪·莫萊
So, Eddie Morra,
你的秘密是什麼      藥物
What's your secret?        Medication,
我在服用某種特殊藥物
I'm on special medication,
好的
OK,
某種特殊的復合配方
Well, it's a formula with a complex method,
當然 調研 大量的調研也是其中一部分
But, of course, research was a component, Massive research,
我清楚瞭解自己購買公司的每一絲架構
I knew every helix of every scrap of DNA in every company I bought,
我辦公室的資料堆積如山 知道這意味著什麼嗎
Papers stacked like the Himalayas in my office, and you know what?
股價上漲      說對了一點
The stocks went up,        By a hair,
沒錯 股價是在上漲 但誰願意為某個
Sure, the stocks rose, but who wants to do all that work
毫無遠見的領導者工作
for a shitty little uptake?
你想要的並不是
It's not the visceral kind of spike you want
短期的持有或是增長...
in short term holdings so...
...拋棄所有的統計數據
...I dispensed with all the hard statistics
我直接在市場傳聞中捕捉需要的信息
and I went right to the rumor mill,
你的股票都是這樣買進的嗎
So you bought your stocks based on what?
街邊的小道消息?
The tom-toms beating in the street?
自然 股價的高低並非真正基於公司的運營狀況
Sure, Share prices aren't really based on how a company works,
更多的是對群眾心理的把握
It's about how mass psychology works,
所以如果我發現了股價預測的某種計算方式
So, if I found certain algorithms in the perception of the stock...
模式識別 看來這就是你騙人的萬靈油咯
Pattern recognition, That's your snake oil,
但 並非所有人都能理解這種模式
Well, not everybody understands the patterns,
這讓我更具靈性
And that gave me a little bit more of an uptake,
但這也不過是拿不出手的小把戲
but it's just a parlor trick,
然後 我打算另闢蹊徑
So then, I went on to door number three,
你是暗示自己已經找到了某種終端公式嗎
Are you really implying that you have some sort of ultimate formula?
好吧 10天裡 從一萬兩千到兩三百萬的累積
Well, from 12,000 to 2,3 million in ten days,
我自然有公式 皮爾斯先生      誇大妄想
I do have a formula, Mr. Pierce,        Delusions of grandeur,
我並非誇大妄想
I don't have delusions of grandeur,
我有的是宏偉建築的詳細計劃
I have an actual recipe for grandeur,
我不知道你是誰 也不清楚你的把戲
I don't know who you are, Eddie, or what you game is,
但有一點我很肯定
but I'm sure of one thing,
你並不是我會任而用之的人
You don't work in my world,
我太熟悉所謂的投資人
I'm up to my ass with investment guys
你不像他們是惶恐不安
and you don't have their half-terrified,
和妄自尊大的混合體...
half-cocky line of crap which is...
...但這並不意味著我會更欣賞你
...not to say that I like yours any better,
但顯而易見的是 你以一種
But you obviously pick your stocks
我從未見識過的方式選擇股票
in a way which I haven't seen before,
看看這些公司 然後告訴我你的想法
Take a look at these companies and tell me what you think,
現在嗎      是的 你可以慢慢來
Right now?        Yeah, Take your time,
當然
Sure,
這些公司並不是問題所在 對嗎
These companies aren't the question, are they?
解釋下
Explain,
除非你兩邊都有插手
Unless you're playing both sides of the fence,
控制住整個能源市場 但是 不對
Control the whole power enchilada, but, no,
這些公司並不足以讓你入主
these companies wouldn't get you there in emerging markets,
你還必須...哦 喔哦
You would have to... Oh, Whoa,
一定是了 你深思熟慮過的某種合併大案子
This must be some big-ass merger you're contemplating,
真正有能力和范隆合作的
And there's really only one company with enough bling
只有一家公司
to justify a merger with Van Loon and Associates,
你以為是在和誰說話
Who have you been talking to?
哦 我只是將線索連接
Oh, I'm just connecting the dots,
漢克·阿特伍德真的會同意嗎
Is Hank Atwood really gonna go for it?
嗯 你要麼是個驚人的詐騙藝術家
Well, you're an amazing con artist,
要麼就是個聰明絕頂的年輕人
or you're a very smart young man,
行了 你們兩個合作?
I mean, come on, The two of you together?
整個世界就會像奧利弗·特維斯特一樣
The whole world would have to come begging for energy
端著破碗向你們乞討能源
like Oliver Twist and his bowl of gruel,
你現在是倒退了 還看出什麼
Now you're going backwards, What else you got?
預言 這行不通的      為什麼
A prediction, It won't come off,        Why's that?
除非能放棄利比亞      真的嗎
You'd have to back off Libya,        Really?
好吧 你不會想從搭你便車的笨蛋那裡
Well, you don't want to hear this from some schmuck
聽到這些信息
who needs a ride home,
好吧 你贏了
All right, you get your shot,
明早10點聖瑞吉酒店見
Meet me tomorrow at the Saint Regis at ten
讓我看看這位貪婪的搭便車的小笨蛋
and tell me how the gutsy little schmuck who needs a ride home
會如何重組這些交易 你最好做好充分的準備
would re-structure these deals, And you'd better be prepared,
悉聽尊便
I'm at your disposal,
你不會真住在這裡吧
You don't really live here, do you?
嗯...艱苦樸素通常不怎麼喜聞樂見
Well... Spartans weren't big on amenities,
是的 他們通常會摔得很慘
Yeah, and they eventually got their asses kicked,
我沒有進屋 更想四處走走 消化再吸收
I didn't go in. I wanted to walk, move, digest, ingest.
生活中就是有這樣的時候
There are moments in life...
你清楚自己離成功只有一步之遙
moments when you know you've crossed a bridge.
你過去的失敗已成過往
Your old life is over.
而范隆就是我的那一步 我終於走到了這裡
Van Loon was my bridge. I finally had my shot.
華爾街會提供所需的一切 但我又能走多遠呢
Wall Street would provide my nest egg, but then how far could I go?
CEO 全球力量 也許還能是總統
CEO? A global force? Maybe President.
是到了有人來撼動這個世界 完成事業的時候了
Time somebody shook up the free world and got things done.
突然之間...
Suddenly...
又是一個跳躍 我怎麼走過了20個街區呢
It was another skip. How had I gone the last 20 blocks?
又是10個 然後...
I got another ten blocks. And then...
...又到了住宅區
...I was way uptown.
這是哪個酒吧
What bar was this?
...黑色的油畫布 這樣他們能將所有的顏料...
...black canvas and then they would just drop all the paint...
是的 你有沒有見過...
Yeah, Did you ever meet...
...然後我就去吃午飯了 回家...
...and then I actually went there and had lunch, I went back,
我的朋友都財源滾滾...
My friends are rolling...
聽說你很喜歡派對
I heard you like to party.
嘿 小心點      嘿 嘿 別激動
Hey, watch it,        Hey, hey! Take it easy!
打架? 我應該不會的
A fight? Don't know how to fight.
不過 真的不會嗎
Or do I?
用手指勾伸入嘴內部
You use the fishhook action to get inside the mouth.
就像這樣
Like this.
攻擊敏感區域 眼睛 咽喉 腹股溝
Attack the sensitive areas. The eyes, the throat, the groin.
一旦得手 不要停止
If you are hit, do not stop.
你的堅持不懈會讓襲擊者退縮
Your persistence will discourage your attacker.
讓對手失去平衡
Off-balancing your opponent
並利用他的衝力 帶倒他
and then using his momentum, take him down.
當一切靜止的時候
When it finally stopped,
我完全無法拼湊出生命中過去的18個小時
I couldn't account for the last 18 hours of my life.
嘿 是我 我本以為你會來
Hey, it's me. I thought you were coming over.
你還好嗎 接到留言給我電話
Is everything OK? Call me when you get this.
即便沒有NZT 我仍決定嘗試研究范隆的文件
Even off NZT, I decided to give Van Loon's files a shot.
卻發現根本就是天書一般的存在
They were hieroglyphs.
喂      凱文 我是艾迪
Hello?        Kevin, this is Eddie.
艾迪      聽我說
Eddie?        Listen,
今天我去不了了      你在說什麼
I can't make the meeting today.        What are you talking about?
我今天去不了 我病了
I can't come in today, I'm sick,
哦 你不會現在就得了流感吧
Yeah, well you can't have the flu right now,
他不會再給我們第二次機會的
He'll never give you this chance again,
我知道 聽著 只是...還有數據要分析
I know, listen, I just... I have all this data to analyze...
那你昨天去幹了什麼
What have you been doing for the last day?
凱文 我...      你不明白嗎 這是對你的測試
Kev, I...        Don't you get it? This is your test,
是的 我明白 但此時此刻我無法通過這個測試
Yeah, well, I can't pass the test right now,
如果你不行 我要怎麼辦
And how am I gonna look if you don't?
我明白 聽我說 我只是...      你安靜聽我說
I know, listen, I just...        Sh, Listen to me,
收拾好你自己 準時來赴約
Pull yourself together, Get down to the meeting,
好吧 好吧 我去 我會去的
OK, OK, I'll be there, I'll be there,
嘿 你好      艾迪
Hey, how are ya?        Eddie,
很高興再次見到你
Good to see you again,
請坐
Sit down,
你對漢克·阿特伍德瞭解多少
What do you know about Hank Atwood?
阿特伍德 嗯...
Atwood, um...
他是個傳統叛逆者 嗯...
He's an iconoclast, um...
擁有大半科羅拉多州的財富
Owns about half of Colorado,
這就是你精心準備的結果嗎 艾迪
So this is prepared, Eddie?
嗯...
Uh...
算是阿特伍德入門知識嗎
Is this Atwood 101?
還有誰不認識阿特伍德的嗎
Doesn't everybody know about Atwood?
他兩年前在哪裡
Where was he two years ago?
嗯      哪裡都不是
Hm?        Nowhere,
兩年前他還沒在福布斯的榜上
Two years ago he wasn't even on Forbes' radar,
巨大的飛躍 不是嗎
That was a great leap forward, right?
我看不懂這傢伙 他就這麼憑空竄出 強勢有力
I'm baffled by this guy, He comes out of nowhere so strong,
在我還沒機會深入敵營之前 就讓我疲於應對了
Has me on the run before I can even get to anybody in his camp,
在兩項產業上 給了我沉重一擊
Beats me out of two properties,
投資了毫無原油資源 更是我從未觸及的領域
investing in countries with no oil, Places I'd never go near...
我們現在位於一家酒店的門口
We're here in front of the hotel where a woman,
昨晚 一位名叫瑪利亞·溫貝裡的女性
identified as Maria Winberg,
被證實死於酒店房間
was found dead in her room last night,
成為不法行為的受害者
a victim of foul play.
溫貝裡女士是知名的社交名媛 模特...
Ms. Winberg was a well-known socialite and model...
...更因其樂衷慈善而譽滿全城
...but was also known for her dedicated charity work around the city.
警方花費了數個小時詢問酒店僱員及顧客
Police spent hours questioning hotel staff and patrons
有目擊證人證實目睹一名男人離開現場...
and an eyewitness reported seeing a man leaving the scene...
...能否幫我說服他可以和我合作
... help me convince him that I can raise his game,
你有什麼意見嗎
Got any ideas?
你怎麼看
What do you think?
酒店內設置了足夠的監控錄像...
Hotel has adequate security cameras...
艾迪 你不是這種人吧 是不是
You're not one of those kind of guys, are you Eddie?
房間裡擺個電視就能讓你思想分散嗎
We lose you if there's a screen in the room?
我們的世界正在悄無聲息地發生改變
These are tectonic plates that are shifting right under us,
抱歉 容我暫離片刻
Pardon me, one second.
可能嗎 我殺人了?
Was it possible? Could I have killed someone?
真是我幹的?
Was it even me?
艾迪? 我是梅利莎
Eddie? This is Melissa.
弗農不會給過你什麼吧
Listen, Vernon hasn't been giving you anything, has he?
那東西很危險
Because that stuff is dangerous.
梅利莎?
Melissa?
梅利莎 我們能找地方見面嗎
Melissa, hey, do you think that we can meet somewhere?
我需要和你談談      我們正談著呢
I really need to talk to you,        We're talking now.
不是這樣的 中午在...
No, no, let's meet at, uh...
格蘭特的比利餐廳碰頭怎麼樣
Billy's on Grant at noon?
你不能見我      不 不...
You can't see me, Eddie.        No, no...
拜託 艾迪      拜託 來吧 我...
Eddie, please.        Please, please come, please come, I...
這很重要 我需要弄明白你的意思
It's important, I really need to know what you're talking about,
我意識到也許還有其他人知道NZT的存在
I realized that there were other people who might know about NZT.
弗農的其他客戶
Vernon's other clients.
你好      你好
Hi.        Yeah, hi,
我想找一下傑瑞·布萊迪
may I please speak with Jerry Brady?
傑瑞住院了      他怎麼了
Jerry's in the hospital.        He's what?
他的病情非常不樂觀
Yeah, he's not doing well at all.
你好 請問保羅·卡普蘭在嗎      不 他不在
Yeah, hello, is Paul Kaplan there?        Uh, no. No, he's not.
保羅三天前去世了
Uh, Paul passed away three days ago.
我的天 請節哀
Oh, my God, I'm so sorry,
起初他感覺頭疼 隨後在工作中倒下
Yeah, he started getting headaches, then he collapsed at work.
現在他在重癥監護室
Now he's in the ICU.
請代我問候他 謝謝
OK, please give him my best, Thank you,
我電話問過的人當中 三個死了 其餘病重
Of all the people I called... three were dead and the rest were sick.
喂 喂
Hello? Hello?
小心點 哥們兒!
Watch it, man!
你看到了嗎
Did you see that?
喂!
Hey!
快走! 快走!
Go! Go!
艾迪
Eddie,
梅利莎
Melissa,
嗨
Hey,
別說我容光煥發 因為我知道
Don't tell me I look good, 'cause I know,
自己不希望你見到我這鬼樣子
I didn't want you to see me this way,
你看上去挺好
You look good,
我...
Oh, I, uh...
是啊 我重新振作了起來
Yeah, I sorta got myself together,
NZT就有這個效果
NZT will do that to you,
你這是什麼意思      我的意思是 我也吃了
What do you mean?        I mean, I took it, too,
弗農什麼也沒告訴你 對嗎
Vernon didn't tell you any of this, did he?
沒有
No,
他和我提起這種神奇新藥的時候
Well, when he told me about this amazing new drug,
我正處於人生谷底 而它 確實太神了
I was like, down the hatch, And it was, It was amazing,
我45分鐘就讀完了布萊恩·格林的"宇宙的琴弦"
I read Brian Greene's The Elegant Universe in 45 minutes
並且能夠理解消化
and I understood it,
轉瞬之間我的工作效率瘋狂提升
My work rate increased just insanely overnight
我老闆為此恨死我了
and my boss started to hate me,
上面把他的位置給了我 然後...我開始感到恐懼
They offered me his job and then... and then I got scared,
為什麼      為什麼 因為我不蠢
Why?        Why? Because I'm not stupid,
沒人能負擔如此高速的大腦運轉而不崩潰
Nobody can operate at that level of mental activity and not crash,
我停止了服藥
I stopped taking it,
然後呢      然後我就病了 頭疼
And?        And I got sick, Headaches,
嘔吐 於是我又去找弗農
Throwing up, So I went back to Vernon,
他告訴我所有服用的人都在陸續死去
He told me about all the people that were dying,
你吃了多少 艾迪
How much have you been taking, Eddie?
吃了很多
I've been taking a lot,
那也許...也許他們解決了那個缺陷 也許...
Well, maybe... maybe they've worked out the bugs, Maybe...
也許那不是同一批藥
Maybe this is a different batch,
也許吧      你現在沒服用了 對吧
Yeah,        You're off it right now, aren't you?
先把你的故事講完
Just finish your story,
...我沒再服用 也就活了下來
...I didn't take any more and I didn't die,
但過了一段時間 我發現自己再也無法
But after a while, I realized I couldn't concentrate on anything
集中精力超過十分鐘
for longer than ten minutes,
我...我趕不上截稿日期 懶惰 拖拖拉拉
I, uh... I missed deadlines, got lazy, slow, so slow,
那是兩年前的事了
That was two years ago,
而我到現在都還沒恢復過來
And I haven't been the same since,
你的藥還有剩餘嗎 很好
Do you have some left? Good,
回家馬上吃了
You go home and you take it,
不要停止服藥
You take the dose down, but you don't just stop,
停止服藥你就死定了
You'll die if you just stop,
逐漸降低服藥量 否則頭疼只是噩夢的開始
Try to taper off, otherwise the headaches are just the beginning,
我得走了
I have to go,
你知道誰發明了這個藥嗎      我不知道
Do you know who makes it?        I don't know,
我得走了
I have to go,
該死 聽我說 聽我說 好吧
Oh, shit, Listen, listen, listen, Listen, listen, listen... OK,
你忘記我的事了?      沒有 沒有
You forget about me, huh?        No, no, no, no,
12點你沒出現
12:00 and you're not here,
我現在來了      很好
I'm here now, Oh!        Good,
快點 趕緊走      我可以給你開支票
Come on, get going,        I could write you a check,
支票 支票 你腦子進水了?
Check, Check, Are you out of your mind?
你以為我是幹什麼的 做正經融資的嗎
What do you think I am? Some financial institution?
好吧 你說得對 我們只需要去家銀行
All right, You're right, Look, we just need to go to a bank...
那是什麼玩意兒
What do you got there?
那是什麼      只是阿司匹林
What is it?        No, it's just aspirin,
看上去可不像阿司匹林 是好東西 對吧
Don't look like no aspirin I ever see, It's something good, huh?
我感覺不錯 那到底是什麼
I feel good, man, What's in this stuff?
只是維生素和阿司匹林
It's just, uh, vitamins and aspirin,
純屬胡說八道 艾迪小子
You full of shit, Eddie baby,
琳迪 我沒讓他進來 但是...
Lindy, I wouldn't have let him in, but...
抱歉      泰勒 抱歉先掛了
I'm sorry...        Tyler, I gotta go,
我病了
I'm sick,
我不該來的... 抱歉 但我走不回家了
I shouldn't... I'm sorry, I couldn't make it home,
我們馬上去醫院      不 不 不
Let's get you to a hospital,        No, no, no, no, no, I don't need...
我需要你去拿...
I need you to get...
非常簡單 我需要服藥
It's really simple, babe, I need my pills,
艾迪 什麼藥      我不...寶貝 這一言難盡
Eddie, what pills?        I don't... Babe, it's complicated,
你在服什麼藥 吸毒嗎
What are you taking? Are you on drugs?
它們是...它是...
They're... it's...
我別無選擇 只好向琳迪坦白一切
I had no choice. I told Lindy everything.
你所有的精力 注意力
So all this energy of yours, all this focus...
...都源自一種藥物
...has been a drug,
它應該是合法的
Well, it was supposed to be legal,
我還有...一批存貨
I have a... a supply stashed,
你希望我去幫你拿來
You want me to go get it,
不 不 不 我自己去拿      給我鑰匙
No, No, no, no, I'm gonna go get it,        Give me your keys,
我這就去你的公寓
I'll go to your apartment,
不在...我公寓裡 我把它轉移了
It's not... in my apartment, I moved it,
好吧 那你藏在哪裡了
OK, so where did you move it?
藏在我家裡
In my house,
真是不可思議
Unbelievable,
喂 你拿到了嗎
Hey, have you got it?
是的
Yeah,
有人在跟蹤我
There's someone following me,
你確定嗎
Are you sure?
是的 他上了我後面那輛出租車
Yeah, He got into the cab behind me
從頭到尾跟著我
and he's making every turn I'm making,
寶貝 報警      你能甩掉他嗎
Baby, call the cops,        Can you go around him?
親愛的 怎麼了
Babe, what's happening?
堵在路上了
We're stopped dead,
他從車上下來了
He's getting out,
艾迪 他走過來了
Eddie, he's walking over here,
琳迪?
Lindy?
我的天!
Oh, God!
救命! 救命!
Help! Help!
這個男人...他在跟蹤我!
This man's... This man's chasing me!
他跟著我出了我家 可我不認識他
He followed me from my building, I don't know him,
拜託!      喂 老小子 別找她麻煩!
Please!        Yo, buddy, let's leave her alone!
你聾了嗎 我說別找她麻煩!
Are you deaf? I said leave her alone,
喂 老小子 你這是想把我惹毛嗎
Hey, buddy, are you trying to piss me off?
你在幹什麼 混蛋?
What are you doing, man?
你沒掛吧      我沒掛 怎麼了
Are you still there?        Yeah, I'm here, What happened?
我被困住了 他遲早找到我
I'm stuck, He'll find me,
好 別說話了 別動
OK, stop talking. Don't move.
他殺了兩個人      什麼
He killed two guys.        What?
他也會殺了我的      不 不 不會的
He's gonna kill me, too,        No, no, no...
他能看見你嗎
Can he see you?
看不見
No,
暫時還看不見
Not yet,
我不知道要怎麼辦才好
I don't know what to do,
好 我要你打開袋子吃一顆藥
OK, I need you to go into the bag and take one of the pills,
為什麼
Why?
因為那樣你就知道該怎麼辦了 吃了你就明白了
Because you'll know what to do. You'll take it and then you'll know.
他手裡有刀 艾迪 我不覺得自己能刀下逃生
He's got a knife, Eddie, I can't think my way out of a knife,
聽我的話 30秒鐘後藥就會生效
Just listen to me, It'll come on in 30 seconds,
然後你再思考要怎麼脫身 藥就有這個功效
And you'll think your way out, That's what it does,
他越走越近了
He's getting closer,
琳迪 我愛你
Lindy, I love you,
嗨
Hey!
現在轉過來...
Now turn to me...
你要幹什麼!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
啊!      爸爸!
Ah!        Daddy!
艾迪 給
Eddie, Here,
沒事了
It's gonna be OK,
我們得離開這裡 艾迪?
We've got to get out of here, Eddie?
你沒事吧
You OK?
沒事
Yeah,
對於那件事我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry about what happened,
我希望你明白我們再也不會經歷那種事了
I want you to know that you never, ever have to go through that again,
因為我會照顧好我們倆的
'cause I can take care of us now,
我相信你可以
I'm sure you can,
我能保證我倆的安全 我又恢復了 好嗎
I can make us safe, I'm back, OK?
誰恢復了 艾迪      我呀
Who's back, Eddie?        Me,
不 那不是你
No, It's not you,
你以前不是這個樣子      我依舊是我 琳迪
You were different before,        I'm still the same person, Lin,
而我不是了 藥效發作的時候
I wasn't, when I was on it,
我做出了自己平時絕對做不到的事
I did things I would never do,
那些事救了你的命      但那本不是我能做到的
Those things saved your life,        But they weren't me,
是的 是你做到的 藥是那樣發揮...
Yes, they were, No, the way it works...
我知道它是怎麼發揮功效的
I know how it works, I get it,
我完全明白 你覺得自己所向無敵
I totally get it, You feel invincible,
它能讓我們取得多大的成功 你根本無法想像
Where it will take us, Lin, you can't even imagine,
我們能做到的事情 我們一年後能成為怎樣的人
The things we'll be able to do, Where we'll be a year from now,
我們終將能過上的那種上等人的生活
The kind of life that we'll finally be able to live,
那你恐怕得獨自享受了
Well, you might have to live it without me,
我會戒掉的 只是現在需要解決些事情
Look, I am gonna stop taking it, There's just some things I have to do
確保我倆的安全 安排好一切 然後我就會戒
to keep us safe and that... To set us up and then I'm gonna get off it,
我本來就是這麼打算的      艾迪
I mean, that's the plan,        Eddie...
我真的都打算好了 我發誓
Look, I have a plan, I swear,
我會戒的
I'm gonna get off it,
好吧
OK,
我希望你能做到
I hope you do,
要找我嗎
Looking for me?
你以為你能跑掉 是嗎
You think you can run out on me, huh?
你以為我不知道你躲在哪裡
You think I don't know where you are?
我認為我們之間的生意已經做完了
I was under the impression our business was settled,
再給我些那種藥
I want some more of that stuff,
不然我就當場崩了你 自己選
Or I shoot you right here, Take your pick,
這傢伙是打發不走的
This guy was not going away.
給他幾片藥能為我爭取到時間
A few pills would buy me some time.
給 我們兩清了      走著瞧吧
There it is, We're done,        Oh, yeah, We'll see,
直到我找到更...長久的解決辦法
Until I found a more... permanent solution.
除非我真的身陷險境
Unless you see a real threat,
我不希望能察覺到自己身邊有保鏢
I never want it known that I have any security,
你們不需要為我開道 只需要跟著我
You'll never precede me, you'll always follow me,
永遠不要遠於15步 兩人也不要靠得太近
Never more than 15 steps behind, And never stand too close together,
我希望自己回頭的時候還能看見你倆之間有空隙
I want to able to look behind me if the opportunity presents itself,
不要穿同樣顏色的西裝 這不是什麼黑客帝國
And don't wear the same color suit, This isn't The Matrix.
你得明白 艾迪 我把你打發了
You have to know, Eddie, I wrote you off,
我當時病了      你沒資格生病
I was sick,        You don't get sick,
生意做到這份上 有口氣就得上 你還沒死呢
You're playing at this level, you get hit by a car, you don't even die,
你說得完全正確      我知道我是對的
You're absolutely right,        I know I'm right,
我都不知道我在和誰浪費時間
I mean, I didn't know who or what I was talking to,
我當時燒到40度 卡爾 神志恍惚
A hundred and five, That's who you were talking to, Carl, Delirium,
對
Mm-hm,
我把修改過的預測發過來了
I sent over my revised projections,
我沒讓你發什麼預測
I didn't ask for your projections,
我明白 但只要你看過了的話...
I know, but I think if you take a look at them...
我已經看過了 事實上
I already have, As a matter of fact...
我已經根據你的預測炒掉了一些人
...I fired a few people over your projections,
我很抱歉      不 你才沒有
I'm sorry,        No, you're not,
你慶幸自己知道我的團隊沒留意的事
You're relieved that you know things my team missed,
這一刻 一切簡直不可思議...
The minute, the instant that's no longer true...
服用NZT兩個月後
Two months after I'd started NZT,
我主持了商業史上最大的合併計劃
I was brokering the biggest merger in corporate history.
諷刺的是 關鍵在於原油
Ironically, it's gonna be crude,
原油是我們切入的最佳方位
Crude is gonna be where we're gonna hit them,
這部分利潤高達百分之兩百
Which yields a prospective profit of 200 percent,
這會讓每個人都喜出望外
That makes both of us very happy campers,
我發現只要保持合理攝入量
I found that if I maintained an even dose,
按時吃飯 不沾酒精
remembered to eat, drank no alcohol,
頭腦空窗期就再沒發生過      你還好吧 艾迪
the blackouts didn't recur.        How you doing, Eddie?
湯姆 衣服裡能加暗袋嗎
Tom, is it possible to construct an imperceptible compartment?
在這件上面嗎
In this jacket?
所有衣服上面      當然可以 先生
In all of them,        Certainly, sir,
與其在這裡坐吃山空
Safer though my stash now was,
不如先想辦法
I was not sitting around until it ran out.
我能按同樣的配方製作出同樣的藥物嗎
Can I combine these ingredients in the same exact quantity,
當然可以 不過
yes, but,
它能否起到同樣的作用...不好說
the exact method of delivery to the brain... Darts at a dartboard,
什麼意思      還需要臨床試驗 在人身上試驗
Meaning?        Clinical trials, guinea pig people,
花的時間太久了      製藥就這麼麻煩
That's gonna take too long,        It's what it is,
不然就是在草菅人命 需要12到18個月...
Or you'll kill people, You need 12, to 18 months...
如果你六個月裡能做出來我就給你兩百萬
I'll give you two million dollars if you can do it in six,
我發現我們能降低30%的成本
I found that we can cut costs 30 percent and, um...
失陪一下
Excuse me one second,
我以為之前那事已經解決了 偵探
I thought we straightened this out, Detective,
這和弗農·甘特無關 莫萊先生
This isn't about Vernon Gant, Mr. Morra,
那又是為了什麼
What is this about?
瑪利亞·溫貝裡案的目擊證人指認這人為嫌疑犯
The witness identified the Maria Winberg suspect as this person,
打算告訴我你四月二日晚上在什麼地方嗎
Wanna tell me your whereabouts the night of April 2nd?
我沒辦法再獨自隱瞞下去
I couldn't keep this quiet on my own.
於是我請了莫裡斯·布蘭特 紐約最出色的律師
Enter Morris Brandt... the most lethal lawyer in New York.
很幸運房間已經打掃過了
You're lucky somebody wiped the room,
證據薄弱 最多只能算間接旁證
It's weak, Circumstantial at best,
和我私下透個底 你那天在那裡嗎
Just between us, were you there?
我記不得了
I don't remember,
我無意對你們讓步...
I don't want to make concessions to you...
卡爾·范隆和漢克·阿特伍德
Carl Van Loon and Hank Atwood
都對我即將受到謀殺指控毫不知情
had no idea I might soon be charged with murder.
但SY 艾丹這幾家公司
But SyCorps, Andine and others are jockeying
都正在為我們裝作沒有察覺到的
for the same industrial concessions in Libya
商業利益在利比亞大打出手
that both our companies are pretending we're not sniffing out,
你怎麼知道呢
How do you know this?
自上而下收取賄賂的政府本身就腐敗不堪 自然
The governmental bribe system is itself corrupt, so, of course,
內線消息 像任何東西一樣 都是買得到的
information about its inner workings, like anything, can be bought,
繼續
Go on,
如果你看看左下角那排 在2008年
If you take a look at the lower left-hand column, in 2008,
在我們留意到前
five companies were jockeying for a position
已經有五個公司在角力了
before we even took notice,
老天 他看上去不堪一擊
Jesus, he looks frail,
可能是裝出來的      他還不到60歲
Could be an act,        He's not even 60,
決定好了嗎 艾迪 你準備怎麼辦
So, have you decided, Eddie? What are you gonna do?
併購結束之後? 我不知道
When this is over? I don't know,
你還沒告訴我答案
You haven't given me the answer,
你又沒有問
You haven't asked the question,
基於我的貢獻
Well, given the scale of my contribution,
45吧
let's say 45,
成交 四千五千美元
Done, Forty-five thousand dollars,
四千萬是一大筆錢 艾迪
Forty million is plenty, Eddie,
但那之後還會有更多
There's a lot more where that came from,
知道嗎 艾迪
You know, Eddie...
也許你考慮的是
...it may be on your mind
不準備繼續為我工作
that you're not gonna continue to work for me anymore,
這是一次寶貴的學習經歷
This has been the learning experience of my life,
我希望如此 我希望你不會覺得自己已經學得夠了
I hope it has, I hope you don't think you've gotten enough from me,
進入下一階段
On to the next,
要發展職業生涯 我必須不斷前行
Well, in order for a career to evolve, I'm gonna have to move on,
你想過沒有這只會告訴我
That you would even think that would only show me
你完全沒有準備好獨自前行
how unprepared you are to be on your own,
我是說 你清楚認識到自己是個怪才
I mean, you do know you're a freak,
你那源於天賜 或者機遇 或者基因
Your deductive powers are a gift from God, or chance,
或者其他任何來源的推理能力
or a stray shot of sperm, or whatever, or whoever the hell wrote
都不是你辛苦掙來的
your life script, a gift not earned,
你不懂我明白的事因為你的能力不是磨練出來的
You do not know what I know because you have not earned those powers,
你對你的能力毫不珍惜
You're careless with those powers,
你揮灑賣弄自己的能力
You flaunt them and you throw them around
就像富二代揮霍他的遺產
like a brat with his trust fund,
你沒有經歷過一梯梯往上爬的日子
You haven't had to climb up all the greasy little rungs,
你沒有被投資人的無聊折磨過
You haven't been bored blind at the fundraisers,
你也沒有為了
You haven't done the time
把你第一次婚姻費在做個鳳凰男身上
in that first marriage to the girl with the right father,
你覺得自己可以輕鬆跨越這些階段
You think you can leap over all in a single bound,
你從不需要為了一個位置使勁渾身解數
You haven't had to bribe or charm or threaten your way
去行賄 色誘 威脅
to a seat at that table,
你不知道要怎麼分析你的競爭對手
You don't know how to assess your competition
因為你從未真正競爭過 別指望你有本事和我爭
because you haven't competed, Don't make me your competition,
現在 我會給你一筆資金
Now, I'll open up a line of credit for you,
你會想試試身手的
You'll be wanting a few toys,
住酒店已經不再是個辦法
Hotel rooms were no longer an option.
我需要的是個堡壘
What I needed was a bunker.
有內置保險箱 中央監控系統
There's a built-in safe, central surveillance,
金庫級別的空氣壓力門
vault grade pneumatic doors.
絕無僅有的三層保全系統
It's an unparalleled three-tier security system,
這是一座風景絕美的堡壘
A fortress with a hell of a view,
開價多少      八百五十萬
What's the asking price?        Eight-point-five,
我買了
I'll take it,
毫無疑問他是為NZT而來
Right away, it was obvious he was on NZT.
下周我需要20片藥
Next week, I'm gonna need 20 pills,
下周 你可以去見鬼
Next week, you can go fuck yourself!
不是說你會舒坦
Not that you'd feel anything,
我不認為你那些富豪朋友會喜歡
I don't think your Fortune 500 financial friends would appreciate
你和警察之間的那點小小糾紛的
the details of your little dilemma with the police,
週四 藥送到這裡
Thursday, I'm gonna need the pills here,
變聰明了啊
Getting smarter!
顯而易見 不能再這麼繼續下去
Obviously, this could not go on,
不過這世上
but there is very little on this earth
四千萬美金解決不了的事情可不多
that 40 million dollars can't solve.
明早九點鐘 阿特伍德就會簽字
And tomorrow at nine, Atwood would sign the papers.
這是怎麼回事      臨陣退縮?
Do you want to call it?        Cold feet?
現在這麼說已經太晚了
There was all last night to tell us that,
有消息嗎      我馬上再聯繫他 先生
Anything?        I'll call him again, sir.
好吧 他可能會改主意 這也是人之常情
OK, the decision could have changed, That makes sense,
但一聲不吭卻不合理 交易還會進行
The discourtesy doesn't, It's still on,
基於你的那些表格和預測
Oh, based on your charts and projections,
再和我說一遍 你算哪根蔥
You know, remind me, who the fuck are you, anyway?
抱歉 卡爾
I'm sorry, Carl,
我受夠這個裝腔作勢 一文不名的白癡
I've had it with this unqualified, posturing little prick,
閉嘴      什麼時候起這成了裝神弄鬼
Pull it back,        Since when is this the Delphic Oracle?
別說了      打擾一下 范隆先生
Pull it back,        Excuse me, Mr. Van Loon?
阿特伍德夫人在你辦公室等你
Mrs. Atwood is in your office,
阿特伍德夫人 我是卡爾·范隆
Ah, Mrs. Atwood, Carl Van Loon,
我的合夥人 愛德華·莫萊      幸會
My associate, Edward Morra,        Pleasure,
我希望此事盡力保持低調
I wanted to make this as confidential as possible,
當然
Of course,
我丈夫今早突然感到頭痛眩暈
My husband experienced some pain and dizziness this morning,
此刻他正在勒諾克斯山醫院接受檢查
He's currently at Lenox Hill, undergoing tests,
我只是希望表明我們
I just want you to know we have every intention
簽署合同的誠意
of signing the contract,
一旦他能夠簽字 我們立刻辦理
And as soon as he is able, we will proceed,
我知道這是老生常談
I realize this is a useless platitude,
但如果有什麼能效勞的地方
but if there's anything that we can do,
請務必不要見外
please don't hesitate to tell us,
我們無疑希望表現出我們的敬意
Obviously, we want to be as helpful and respectful
阿特伍德夫人
as possible, Mrs. Atwood,
謝謝 先生們 我對此深表感激
Thank you, gentlemen, I rely on your discretion,
看樣子不會有代理簽字了
There won't be a proxy,
不會 像他這種守口如瓶的怎會放權給律師?
No, a cagey prick like him giving away power of attorney?
他最好盡快康復
Well, he'd better get better,
但是阿特伍德不會康復了 因為他沒有NZT
But Atwood wouldn't get better. Because Atwood was out of NZT.
為什麼要驚訝
Well, why be surprised?
還有多少一夜暴富是NZT的功勞
How many other meteoric rises might be explained by NZT?
至少我是這樣
At least I had some.
我的生命沒有受到威脅      在這裡等
My life wasn't in jeopardy.        You can wait here,
但我的財富 我的自由受到了
Only my money. And my liberty.
我和他們談過了
I've been all over with them,
所有嫌疑人不允許有任何
We can't allow any disparity in race
人種或明顯體格上的差異
or physical type between you and the rest of the line up,
好
OK,
我盡力找了些看著像你的克隆體的傢伙
They're as close to your clones as I could possibly get,
目擊證人絕對分不清的
It's gotta be just one big handsome blur to this guy.
誰會在那頭看
Who was out there?
被害人的丈夫嗎
The woman's husband?
酒店員工?
A hotel maid?
我會就此完蛋嗎
Was this how it was all going to end?
毫無頭緒 他根本認不出
Not the dimmest clue, He was dithering,
"他是從右邊數第三個 不 不是他"
"He was the third one from the right, No, Not him,"
給 這西裝真棒 手工定制的?
There you go, It's a thing of beauty, You have that made?
沒錯
I did,
今日市場震盪
...market's been mixed today.
道瓊斯指數因范隆集團和漢克·阿特伍德
The Dow has been yo-yoing amidst speculation that
在協商合併的謠傳而上下震盪
Van Loon Associates and Hank Atwood have negotiated a merger...
你和誰提起過這個嗎
Have you been talking to anyone?
沒有 誰也沒提 卡爾 我又不傻
No, I haven't been talking to anybody, Carl, I'm not stupid,
我知道你不蠢 艾迪
I know you're not stupid, Eddie,
但不要犯所有聰明人會犯的錯
but don't make the classic smart person's mistake,
就是以為沒人能比過你
Thinking no one's smarter than you,
你他媽的去哪兒了
Where the hell have you been?
這是你第二次玩失蹤了
This is the second time you've turned to vapor,
哪兒也沒去 就是去喝個咖啡
I was in the building, I was getting coffee,
怎麼了 有新情況嗎
Why, has there been movement?
是有新情況 阿特伍德陷入昏迷
Yeah, there's been movement alright, Atwood's in a coma,
他沒在耍我們 他確實生命垂危
He wasn't playing us, He's dying,
你對此有什麼看法
What do you know about this?
我一時不知要如何作答
I was less than usually equipped to answer.
遲鈍感逐漸涌上 該再次服用NZT了
The dullness was coming on. I was overdue to take my NZT.
我的頭也開始一陣陣抽痛
And the pain was starting behind my eyes.
失陪一下
Excuse me,
我沒讓你走
You're not excused,
怎麼 你的員工連洗手間也不能去嗎 卡爾
What? A man in your employ can't take a piss, Carl?
是布蘭特還是誰幹的
Was it Brandt or someone else?
在警察局還是什麼更衣間丟的?
The police station? A coatroom?
莫萊先生
Mr. Morra,
卡爾 抱歉...      莫萊先生 莫萊先生!
Carl, I'm sorry...        Mr. Morra, Mr. Morra!
你的包裹 剛送到      是的 什麼
This just came for you,        Yeah, what?
希望不會 有進展通知我
Hope not, so let me know when you know,
好 現在我準備再問你一次 艾迪
All right, I'm gonna ask you again, Eddie,
你對此有何看法
What do you know about this?
什麼 關於洩密嗎      不 關於阿特伍德
What? About the leak?        No, About Atwood,
關於阿特伍德的什麼
What? What about Atwood?
小子 你在撒謊上還嫩得很呢
Look, you got a long way to go as a liar, kiddo,
卡爾 我不知道你在...      聽我說!
Carl, I don't know what you're...        Listen!
我知道你接下來要說的都是廢話
What you're about to say is bullshit,
我知道你有事瞞著我
I know there's something you're hiding from me,
我察覺得到 現在
I smell it on you, Right now,
我想知道為什麼已經板上釘釘的生意打了水漂!
I wanna know why this clusterfuck of a deal is dead in the water!
卡爾
Carl,
艾迪! 艾迪!
Eddie! Eddie!
今天在勒諾克斯山醫院外
Outside Lenox Hill Hospital today,
范隆與阿特伍德的合併出現了更多的變數
more twists and turns in the Van Loon-Atwood merger.
併購僅僅是謠傳
There is absolutely no truth to the rumor of this merger.
絕對沒有 我丈夫正在接受檢查
None whatsoever. My husband is having tests.
這是困難時期
This is a difficult time.
諸位有任何問題可以咨詢我們的律師
We would appreciate your directing further questions to our attorney.
目前無可奉告
Yes, we have no further comments at this time.
我們在等待最新檢測結果
We're just awaiting the results of the latest round of tests
並期待有奇跡發生
and hoping for the best.
謝謝
Thank you.
艾迪 我知道你在家 艾迪
Eddie, I know you're in there, Eddie,
開門
Open up,
快點
Come on,
快開門
Open the door,
於是我就到了現在這地步
And so, here I am.
我知道那藥會一點點將我吞噬
I knew they would kill me slowly and horribly.
但那至少是我的選擇
But this choice would at least be mine.
我們都是本能動物 我們想活下去
But we're instinctive creatures. We want to live.
所以我混沌的大腦努力回憶
So my foggy brain tried to remember
還能在哪裡再找出一片NZT
where one tablet of NZT might be.
這僅僅是個可能 但有這個可能性也就夠了
It was possible. And possible was enough.
你好 艾迪
Hey, Eddie,
你知道我想要更多的藥 為什麼惹我生氣
Now you know I want more, so why would you upset me?
我不喜歡藥快用盡的感覺
I don't like being down to this last one,
你不懂得怎麼利用它
You don't even know how to use it,
你不會物盡其用
You don't appreciate it,
你瞧 我把它溶解成液體
You see, I dissolve in a solution,
一旦注射 直接進入血液和大腦
You shoot it, It goes straight into the blood and brain,
藥效持久得多
Lasts much longer,
那麼
So...
你現在準備告訴我剩下的藥在哪裡了嗎
You gonna tell me where the rest is?
我吃光了
I'm plumb out,
給我找
Go look.
要知道 我的人遲早找到它
You know, these guys are gonna find it,
或者我逼你說出來
Or I'm gonna make you tell me,
問題是 哪種辦法會先奏效呢
Question is, which is gonna come first?
我想我們會知道答案的 對嗎
I guess we're gonna find out, huh?
知道嗎 你在浪費我的時間
This is a waste of my time, you know?
我準備從這行洗手不幹了
I'm getting out of this side of the business,
去拓展新業務 我開了家進出口公司
I'm branching out, I'm starting import-export company,
非常激動人心
Very exciting stuff,
我忙得很 和你耗是你的榮幸
I got a lot on my plate, You're lucky I'm here,
這裡有個保險箱
There's a safe.
要在以前 我會剝了你的皮 割你的肉
Back in the old times, I might peel your skin back, Fillet you,
"割肉" 這詞不錯
"Fillet," It's a nice word,
我以前不知道這詞 哦 那時我的詞彙量真貧乏
I didn't know this before, Oh, I had such a poor vocabulary,
但現在我發現了個好東西 谷歌
But then I discovered this thing, Google,
你知道小腸和大腸一共有20英尺長嗎
Did you know the small and large intestines is 20 foot long?
我不知道 也不相信
I had no idea, I don't believe it,
我要眼見為實 我很多疑 這又是個新鮮詞
I gotta see this for myself, I'm dubious, It's another nice word,
無論如何 我相信你也對此感到好奇
Anyway, I'm sure you're curious, too,
別擔心 都消過毒的
Don't worry, everything's sterilized,
結束之前都不會讓你斷氣的
We're gonna keep you alive for the whole shebang,
你可是身處最佳位置哦 艾迪
You're gonna get a front row seat, Eddie,
怎麼
What?
算不得什麼勝利 不是嗎
Not much of a triumph, was it?
因為死的也有可能是我
Because I would die here, too.
只有NZT能救我
Only NZT could help me
而最後的藥殘存在這個傢伙的血液之中
and the last of it was in this fuck's blood stream.
維克多!
Victor!
什麼
What?
喂!
Hey!
我看不見
I can't see.
在你右邊 開槍
On your right, shoot him.
維克多?
Victor?
警察事後會得知
The police would later note
我公寓的前任主人是個軍火商
that my apartment's previous owner was an arms dealer.
自然 這些闖入者也是對他不滿的客戶
Of course, these intruders had been his dissatisfied clients.
夜還長得很
And the night was still young.
我相信你肯定對你老闆身上發生的事感到好奇
I'm sure you're curious about what happened to your boss,
至少我很好奇
I know I certainly am,
我是說 如果我的律師真在為阿特伍德先生效力
I mean, if my attorney was really working for Mr. Atwood,
想要竭力拯救他的話 他怎麼會死
trying to save his life, why is he dead?
怎麼沒見到這位忠心耿耿的下屬
I mean, at what point was the pony express supposed to ride in
帶著救命靈藥飛奔而來呢
with his life-saving medication?
他的老闆死了
His boss was dead.
因此我再也無關緊要
So, I didn't matter now.
但他不滿莫裡斯·布蘭特
But he did not appreciate that Morris Brandt
獨吞了藥物
had kept the pills for himself.
一切仍有挽回的餘地
And it was all still possible.
十二個月以後
TWELVE MONTHS LATER
實際上 票已售罄
Actually, no, there's no more tickets,
我明白 臨時多出來的募捐人 這倒頭一次
Yeah, I know, An overbooked fundraiser, That's a first,
他剛好過來了 我問問他
Well, here he comes, I'll ask him,
這樣看上去好多了
Oh, that's much better,
非常好      謝謝 先生
Great job,        Thank you, sir,
你好 莫萊先生
Hi, Mr. Morra,
愛德華!
Edward!
我想我們這是要有第二次人滿為患的募捐晚會了
I think we're looking at a second overflow event,
大量捐款不斷涌入 我覺得
There's a wave of donations coming in and I don't think
那些人都沒怎麼猶豫就決定了
they're even gonna try a second debate,
太好了      堅持住
Great.        Hold on,
EC公司的人在你辦公室等你
A guy from Eiben-Chemcorp's in your office,
我約了人吃午餐      他們是你最大的捐助人
I have a lunch,        They're your biggest contributor,
好歹隨便應付下
Give him his two crappy little minutes,
EC製藥?      對
Eiben-Chemcorp Pharmaceuticals?        Yeah,
終於見到了維持這一切運轉的功臣
Finally get to meet the guys that keep the lights on,
卡爾!      莫萊先生
Carl!        Mr. Morra,
真是意外 他們告訴我來的是EC公司的人
What a surprise, They told me somebody from Eiben was coming,
EC公司 沒錯 那現在是我的公司
Chemcorp, Yeah, that's me now,
我在漸漸退出能源市場
I'm moving out of the energy business,
拜託 這就像海夫納離開"花花公子"雜誌一樣
Come on, That's like Hef moving out of the mansion,
幾個月前我買下了EC公司
Yeah, I bought Eiben a couple of months ago,
你竟然沒聽說這事
I'm surprised you didn't hear,
沒有 沒有 他們讓我忙得團團轉
No, No, Well, they really keep me hopping here,
這一切都是有回報的 莫萊議員
Well, it's gonna pay off, Senator Morra,
參議院 誰知道呢...
The Senate, Who knows...
以後又會有何發展 艾迪
Everything's a technicality from here on in, isn't it, Eddie?
我們都知道未來的方向 只要你能維持現狀
I think we both know where it's headed, if you can maintain,
你想過藥用完了之後要怎麼辦嗎
Have you asked yourself what you're gonna do when you run out?
你啥時候知道的      有關係嗎 反正我知道了
When did you know?        Does it matter? I know now,
我真希望你來找的是我 艾迪
I wish you'd come to me at first, Eddie,
我本可以用33塊一股的價格收購EC的
I could have bought Eiben at 33 a share,
我們本可以成為合作夥伴
We could have been partners,
NZT是EC製造的
So, Eiben makes NZT,
官方記錄上沒有這條
Well, it'll never officially exist,
顯然我不需要再指出這對你有什麼好處
Obviously, I don't need to point out the advantages for you,
我想你也許需要
Oh, I think maybe you do,
給你無限供應 我們都知道你別處弄不到了
Limitless supply, We know you can't get any more,
你確定?
You sure about that?
他們今早剛剛關閉了你的實驗室
They shut down your lab this morning,
艾迪 我只是想幫你 僅此而已
Eddie, I just want to help you, that's all,
為你提供源源不斷的藥物
Keep you supplied, No disruption in service,
讓你能安心做事 僅此而已
Give you peace of mind, That's all,
作為回報 我需要做什麼
And in return, I do what?
聽從點建議 也許吧 一開始我不會成天來打擾你
Get a little advice, maybe, I won't be bothering you much at first,
但之後呢 你會拿什麼樣的事來找我
And later, What are you gonna be bothering me with?
既然談到你奮鬥的方向
Well, given where you're heading,
某些主意可能會有點激進
some of our ideas are a bit ambitious,
但是 我認為都是可以實現的
But hey, I think they're achievable,
如果我不喜歡你的主意怎麼辦
And what if I don't like your ideas?
那我們就會說 "祝你成功"
Then we'll say, "Godspeed,"
然後你的生命之燭也許就要風雨飄搖了
And your candle will have shed a brief, but lovely light,
但聽我說 艾迪 我們
But you know what, Eddie, let's not even
現在還是不談這麼遠
go there right now,
現在 我希望讓你保持智慧
Right now, I just want to keep you brilliant...
...健康 來吧 我們一起去吃個飯
...and healthy, Come on, Let's go get some lunch,
你先請 議員
After you, Senator,
謝謝你來拜訪 卡爾
Thanks for stopping by, Carl,
給我們一點時間
Give us a second,
你這是在幹嘛 你想成為美國總統
What are you doing? Do you want to be President of the United States
還是想變成植物人?      我倒願意碰碰運氣
or brain dead, stuck full of tubes?        I'll take my chances,
我說過你沒機會的 我們關閉了你的實驗室
I told you your chances don't exist, We shut down your lab,
你難道沒想過狡兔三窟
You don't think some smartass on NZT
我可能有不止一個實驗室?
might have two or three or even four labs?
那又怎樣 你再也生產不出來了
So what? You're not making any more,
沒錯 我沒再生產了
That's right, I'm not,
我有更好的辦法 一旦你知道了它的成分
I thought better of it, See, once you know what's in it,
你可以調整 重制它 消除缺陷 減少用量
you can tweak it, re-engineer it, Get the bugs out, Taper off,
我完全戒了 卡爾
I'm off it, Carl,
戒或者沒戒
Well, on it or off it,
都不意味著你不能為我工作
there's no scenario where you're not working for me,
你怎麼報償我 用香煙嗎
How you gonna pay me? In cigarettes?
去年一年
Last year you traded
你就交易了17次內幕情報      你在威脅我嗎
inside information 17 times,        You threatening me?
在迪拜開空頭支票 往智利扔工業垃圾
Blank checks from Dubai, Dumping in Chile,
導致官員失蹤
Disappeared officials,
我說 你簡直是站在風口浪尖了...
I mean, you shed a spot light...
你想和我開戰嗎
Do you want to go to war with me?
你給我聽清楚 我不打算扯遠
And trust me when I say this, I'm not even being creative,
但你沒有任何可能在做出這麼多指控之後
There's no way you can be making accusations like that
還能全身而退
and be walking around alive,
這就表明了你找我對陣時
That you would even think that shows me
準備有多麼不充分
how unprepared you are to fight me,
你已經沒有和我對著干的資本了
You're no longer equipped to fight me,
我也許已經脫癮了 但你覺得我什麼也沒學到嗎
I may be off it, but you think I didn't learn anything?
我的神經元沒有進化?
That my synapses didn't change?
我什麼也沒學到?
That I kept absolutely nothing?
你不曉得我會是個多麼可怕的敵人
You have no idea what kind of enemy I can be,
那輛貨車會追那輛出租車的尾      什麼
That van's gonna rear-end that taxi,        What?
那司機在走神 他在發短信 時速是30英里/小時
The driver's distracted, He's texting, He's going 30 miles an hour,
需要提前60英尺剎車 沒有足夠減速空間
He has 60 feet to stop, He doesn't have room,
什麼貨車
What van?
我無所不知 卡爾
I see everything, Carl,
我比任何人都看得更長遠
I'm 50 moves ahead of you and everybody else,
你憑什麼認為我不會讓人此刻正用槍指著你
What makes you think I don't have a guy with a bead on you right now?
你怎麼知道你明年這會兒還活著
How do you know you're gonna be alive this time next year?
你在幹什麼 放手 你在幹什麼
What are you doing? You get your hands off me, What are you doing?
心跳有雜音
Something's pumping half-mass in there,
心臟壁腫大
The walls of your heart are dilated,
主動脈瓣狹小 需要進行換心手術
Your aortic valve's steno, So you're gonna need to get that replaced,
但你已經知道了
But you already knew that,
你該為此感到慶幸
You know, you should really be glad about this,
讓我為你工作? 你遲早被我玩弄於股掌之間
'Cause me working for you? You'd end up as my bitch,
也許我們都該冷靜下 然後再談
Maybe we should cool off, Talk again,
我可不這麼認為
I don't think so,
別忘了投票
Don't forget to vote,
愛德華
Edward,
你沒事吧
You good?
沒事 告訴過你我約了人吃飯
Yeah, Told you I have a lunch,
抱歉我遲到了      沒關係
Sorry I'm late,        Hey, Don't worry,
今天過得如何      好多了
How's your day going?        Ah, I've had better,
我還是不習慣你的新髮型
I still can't deal with that haircut,
走在街上都認不出來了
I wouldn't even recognize you on the street,
我改頭換面了
Well, I'm a new man,
我已經點過菜了
I've already ordered,
(這段疑似中文的對話請大家自行想像)
怎麼
What?
破爛熊字幕組
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
歡迎加入